Once upon a time, there was a princess raised by loving parents.
One day, the princess snuck past the guard of the gate and slipped out of the castle for the very first time.
No matter how far she went, however, outside the castle there was only an endless forest as black as pitch.
Before she knew it, the princess ended up unable to either escape the forest or return to the castle.
In that kingdom, the inside of the castle was the entire world.
MUTO
Bakir cast down his sword and found something only he could do.
I want to protect him.
Because he wants to help MUTO.
The pure-hearted MUTO who's always risked himself.
Never giving up, no matter how much he's hurt.
Overcoming the painful memories he wants to forget.
Bakir is strong.
Even if he's not carrying a sword,
Bakir is MUTO's knight.
What's Bakir doing, Sora?
He's talking to the oak tree,
so he can write a story that protects the person who's important to him.
Maybe Bakir really doesn't need help from anyone
and can protect MUTO all by himself.
Can you really say you love me?
Does MUTO's heart just keep getting more and more stained by the raven's blood?
So that he's mean even to Rue?
Poor Rue.
I'm kinda worried about her.
I still can't do anything helpful though.
Hmm.
Duck?
Huh?
Are you okay, Sora?
Are you worrying about me?
Thank you.
Don't worry, I'm okay.
Oh good, Sora.
I thought the teacher might get mad at you, Sora.
What?
You're skipping school with Bakir, Sora!
Ah!
Oh no, I came here thinking I'd check on Bakir on my way to school,
but it's this late already!
Huh?
Yeah, sorry!
Come on, Uzzuru, let's get going!
Okay, Uzzuru, see you later!
Huh?
Ah!
What?
Rue, why is she...
...Uzzura?
Wow!
It's open!
Rue!
Tutu.
Were you just crying?
Of course not.
What are you doing here?
It seemed like you were acting a little strange.
Well, really strange.
Anyway, I mean, this is really dangerous.
Dangerous?
Why would it be?
As you know, I am Cray-hee.
You're Rue!
That's who you are!
That's how I think of you!
I mean...
That scared me.
I'd say you're the one in danger.
Yeah, sure looks that way, huh?
I'm still...
I'm still Princess Cray-hee regardless.
B-B-B-Rue.
Doug!
Where the heck were you?
You're awful!
Huh?
Poor, poor dad!
Dad!
I can't believe you would actually skip point class!
Oh, well, you see...
He's coming!
Don't be scared!
That's scary!
Now, Duck, just wriggle your way out of it.
It's your one hope!
Huh?
Out of what?
He's here!
So, he's come!
So, Miss Duck, it's time we both had a little talk.
It's finally the pro-posal.
What?
Here, Duck, I'll hold your books for you.
Um, uh, thank you.
Now get out there and start wriggling.
Yeah, uh, right.
Miss Duck.
Yes, sir?
Everybody has times when they feel as if they'll never be able to reach their dreams.
Huh?
However, deciding there's no way you can do something is nothing more than a way of comforting
yourself when you lack motivation.
Are you positive you're not fooling yourself about how you feel?
About what is exactly the most important thing to you in the whole world?
I decided to become a girl for Mewtwo, and I became Princess Tutu for Mewtwo.
But somewhere, somehow, I came to the conclusion that I couldn't do anything.
Am I running away?
What's most important to me?
So, if perchance this dream you've been suppressing far too long is to marry me, and your heart isn't
in your lessons because you're agonizing over that, and I, for my part, must reserve a place
to hold the ceremony in once.
Ah!
Thank you for all your help, Mr. Cat.
Goodbye, now.
Goodbye.
Ah!
She squirmed out of it.
It's a big shock for Mr. Cat.
I can't let things stay this way.
I'll search for the heart chart.
I'll search the town.
That's what I can do right now!
It's what I can do for Mewtwo!
Are you the ruler worried about Zora?
What?
Duck said that, Zora!
Duck did?
I already told you there is no Rue.
That's not true!
I don't believe that!
I get this feeling you're still Rue!
You're Rue!
Have I?
Have I met you somewhere before, Zora?
What do you mean?
I've never met a girl like…
Who… are you?
Uzzra!
Is Uzzra Zora?
So do…
Do you actually know…
Do you know if I'm really the Crows?
This is stupid.
I don't have time for this nonsense.
This is some sort of mistake!
Sure, when I investigated Drosselmeyer's family tree,
he was a direct descendant.
But he was only able to find that out
thanks to my taking note of him and showing him myself.
I even know who you people are!
I am far more qualified.
I want you people to acknowledge me.
You who are the stoppers of stories.
The so-called bookmen.
There aren't any qualifications to being human.
That's not my point!
Is this world under the control of Drosselmeyer's stories or not?
Whether living in this world hinders our discernment
doesn't matter to me.
I want to know the truth of this mystery.
There are things it's okay to know
and things that it's not.
Go home.
Damn it.
Let's cut that boy's hands off too.
Just like we did to Drosselmeyer.
Let's cut them off before he starts writing stories.
Patience.
As bookmen, our time is too precious
to be wasting it on fighting false storytellers.
Then let's get the one who exchanges words with the oak tree.
What on earth am I doing?
Father is seeking a heart, and yet I…
Damn it!
So Fakir, he's the one, is he?
Then what was I born into this world for?
What would…
It's so cold.
What's wrong?
You're Rue from the ballet division.
Huh?
Somewhere in this town.
There's gotta be a heart joint somewhere.
Quack!
Who's there?
Just now Mewto's shadow looked like a crow.
Be careful, little duck.
Because for the stoppers of story,
beheading a defenseless little duck
is mere child's prey.
Ho, ho, ho, ho.
What should I do?
What?
Say, what happened to all the other birds?
They just won't come when I call them.
Mewto?
What?
Strange, isn't it?
When here, I love everyone in the world and want to protect them.
The prince's heart.
But I also want to make all the world's love my own.
I wonder which is the real me.
I want people to love me.
But is it okay to just be loved?
I don't know.
My pride is still lost in the dark.
I must overcome this raven's blood in me
and uphold my pride as a prince.
It is my duty to protect all the people.
I want my heart to be whole soon.
Quack, Mewto.
Once I have all the shards of my heart back.
I'm sorry, Mewto.
I swore to get all of your heart back,
but I'm sorry.
I'm going to do my best.
They must be somewhere in this town.
I will find them.
I will.
I'll certainly, definitely,
absolutely, positively find them.
Because that's all I can do.
I can feel your heart beating.
It's rather fast.
Why is that?
Because you're so fragrant.
Come with me.
Okay.
Who are you?
We are the Bookmen.
If you intend to employ Drosselmeyer's power
to spin stories yourself,
we will be forced to stop you.
The Bookmen?
Our ancestors cut off Drosselmeyer's hands
and made him unable to spin stories ever again.
Should his descendant ever try to spin a story,
we must deal him the same fate.
That is the duty that has been passed down to us over generations.
So you're going to cut off my hands then?
Dangerous stories must not be born.
We must stop the stories that already have been born
by burying their endings.
What?
You're the ones responsible for tearing out the story's endings?
Come.
So you're going to cut off my hands, then?
Dangerous stories must not be born.
We must stop the stories that already have been born by burying their endings.
What? You're the ones responsible for tearing out the story's endings?
Come.
I'm not gonna give up yet. I still gotta...
What? A horn shard!
Where? Where?
Oh, maybe it's on the other side of this gate.
Why won't it...
Come on, open up!
It won't open. I wonder if there are other exits.
We're finally here, aren't we?
Yeah!
So this is Gold Crown Town.
Was Mom always an Indian rhinoceros?
You know, you're right. Before we got to this town...
No, there's no way that could be.
Come on!
Yeah, you're right.
Let me get behind!
Yes, Mom!
The gate didn't open just now, did it?
It was like they just suddenly appeared there.
A story's birth is a sudden event.
A start, a happy accident.
So were they suddenly born from the gate?
Yes, this town is most likely controlled by stories, yet we are unable to realize this fact because we're made to believe that whatever we see, no matter how strange, was that way to begin with.
No one but I can dissect this mystery. Therefore, I am the one who's qualified to change the world.
You're right. You do have what it takes to change the world.
You do have what it takes to change the world.
I see. You understand what I'm saying, then?
Since you'll become the blood and flesh of the one who will change the world.
What a truly magnificent girl you are.
This way.
Roo, wait up!
Where are you taking me?
Somewhere. There's got to be another exit somewhere. I know it.
It's no good.
What? Again?
What does this mean?
What's on the other side of this gate?
This one, too.
This one...
There's will be someone ...
And here.
There must be heart shards somewhere outside these gates.
A part in this gate is thro, so I can't, but don't forget.
Heart Shards, where are you?
What? A wall?
What is this?
The grave of the man who played with stories at will,
who broke down the wall between reality and story,
and played with the fates of living people.
This is Strosselmeyer's grave.
We'll cut off both your hands and seal them here.
The outside of Goldcrown Town is nothing but walls?
Stop! Let go of me, damn you!
I have to write!
Stop!
Princess Tutu!
This is...
Thank you.
I'm so glad.
What is this?
What's this? What the hell is going on?
It's dangerous to show yourself before those repugnant people, Princess Tutu.
Drosselmeyer did that?
In the end, everyone's a marionette.
At the moment, I feel somewhat at a loss.
Seems I've...
I've fallen in love with you.
With me?
Yes.
Enough to sacrifice your life?
If it is for your sake.
There's no way what you're saying could be true.
It is!
Listen!
Stop it!
There's no way that I can stop from loving you now.
Just go home.
This emotion isn't for you.
It is!
It's not for you.
It's for you.
It is.
There's no way what you're saying could be true.
It is!
Listen!
Stop it!
There's no way that I could stop from loving you now.
Just go home.
This emotion isn't fake.
I'm sorry, Father, for being a bad daughter, but I... I couldn't do it.
You're that man from the used bookstore.
Before Drosselmeyer lost his hands, he'd already made a device that would enable him to continue weaving stories, even if he lost his body.
The town is being controlled by stories because of that device.
But even we can't discover which parts are real and which are fiction.
However, Princess Tutu, whom no one inside Drosselmeyer's stories was expected to become, appeared and tried to protect you.
And Princess Tutu was taken captive by Drosselmeyer.
By now, this story may have progressed to the point where we can do nothing.
In that case, the only one who can fight is he who carries the same blood.
So the one I'm up against isn't the raven?
Drosselmeyer's story itself is my actual adversary?
May we believe, then, that you are not someone who plays around with stories?
You know, there's still something I feel I'm lacking.
I don't even know what it is I'm lacking, so I can't even start writing.
There's nothing we can do to help you there.
That is a wall you will have to surmount.
If you attempt to lead the story down an abominable path,
we will be forced to carry out our duty once more.
You would do well to remember that.
Drosselmeyer.
The man who plays wantonly with the fates of Mewtwo and everyone else.
Do I really possess enough power in me to fight with him?
Can I save Mewtwo?
Can I bring Tutu back?
You'll fight with me, you say?
You are inside the story?
It would have been best if you'd been torn in two right away.
After all this time, it grinds through a halt.
Now, I suppose there's no helping it without Princess Tutu in the story.
Oh, I must get it running.
Not good, not good at all.
If I thrust this sword into the prince, he might die.
That's fine. If that happens, I too will.
Is this the world where Drosselmeyer is?
That's the prince back when I first met him.
You don't have to worry anymore.
I'm not a crow. I'm a person.
I'm... Rue. My name is Rue.
I can write. I can write a story about her.
I am a puppet who could not have a heart.
All you children who love stories, come gather round.
You're welcome.
Totally, uma espessenia that I will give you to her
I am You are an icon.